instamed.com 2018-05-10

# Privacy Statement - InstaMed

InstaMed Communications, LLC, and its respective divisions, subsidiaries and affiliates (“InstaMed“) recognizes the importance of protecting your privacy. This Privacy Statement (“Statement“) discloses our information-gathering and dissemination practices for this website at www.instamed.com (“Website“).

By using this Website, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Statement and the Terms of Use: https://www.instamed.com/terms-of-use. You may also be subject to another privacy statement or other terms and conditions that are posted on InstaMed’s website specific to a particular InstaMed program or service (“Other Agreement“). Based upon your specific relationship(s) with InstaMed, we may collect, use or disclose Personal Information (defined below) in ways described in more detail in one or more Other Agreements. To the extent the Other Agreement includes additional terms that are not covered by or are inconsistent with this Statement, the terms and conditions of the Other Agreement will supersede this Statement.

Within this Statement you will find covered matters related to the following:

  * Minors
  * Information We Collect
  * Personal Information
  * Non-Personal Information
  * Cookies
  * Third-Party Advertisers
  * How We Use Your Personal Information
  * Disclosure of Your Personal Information
  * Choice to Opt Out
  * Links to Third-Party Sites
  * Security
  * Changes
  * Governing Law and Jurisdiction
  * Contact Information
  * Special Notice to California Residents
  * Do Not Track
  * Third Parties
  * Class Action Waiver

**1\. Minors**

We do not knowingly collect Personal Information (as defined below) online from persons under the age of 18. If a minor provides us with this type of information online, please contact us to have the account deactivated by sending us an email at [support@instamed.com](mailto:support@instamed.com) or by calling us at (866) INSTAMED or (866) 467-8263.

**2\. Information We Collect**

a. Personal Information 

We collect and store Personal Information that you provide voluntarily when using this Website. Personal Information is information that can identify you as a specific individual (“Personal Information”). You are responsible for providing accurate and complete information. For example, you might provide us the following information: responses and survey information and/or site registrations, web portal registration information and payment information. Personal data does not include anonymized aggregate or statistical information from which such identification cannot be reconstituted.

If you create an online account, or request one of our other services, we may collect the following Personal Information: full name, home address, email address, telephone number, social security number, date of birth, and your answers to other similar background information questions, payment information and how you specifically use this Website.

b. Non-Personal Information

When you visit any page on the Website, we use a program that monitors and evaluates the Website website’s traffic. It automatically records every visitor’s host, domain name, pages visited, length of user session, browser type and/or IP address. This information does not contain Personal Information. We use this information to find out how many people visit the Website to determine the areas of greatest interest on the Website, and to make improvements to the Website.

When you visit and interact with this Website, InstaMed and third parties with whom InstaMed has contracted to provide services to InstaMed, may collect non-personal information (for example, a catalog of the site pages you visit, or your IP address).

c. Cookies

As with many other sites, the Website may use “cookies” or other technologies to help us deliver content specific to your interests, to process your inquiries or requests, and/or to analyze your visiting patterns. Cookies, by themselves, will not be used by InstaMed to disclose your individual identity. This information identifies your browser, but not you, to our servers when you visit the Website. If you want to disable the use of cookies or remove them at any time from your computer, you can disable or delete them using your browser (consult your browser’s “help” menu to learn how to delete cookies), however you must enable cookies to access certain information on the Website. Note that in limited instances, such as when you create an online account, or request one of our other services, cookies may contain and be associated with the Personal Information we collect.

We may also collect data by using “pixel tags,” “web beacons,” “clear GIFs” or similar means (collectively, “pixel tags“) that allow us to know when you visit the Website. Through pixel tags, we obtain non-personal information or aggregate information (i.e., your IP address, the areas of this website you visit, your operating system, your browser version and the URL you came from) which can be used to enhance your online experience and understand traffic patterns.

**3\. Third-Party Advertisers**

In addition, we may use third-party advertisers to serve or track advertisements on other websites. Please note that these third parties also may use cookies, pixel tags and other technologies to, among other things, enable such third parties to record which ads your browser has loaded and which site pages you may have been viewing when the ads were delivered or accessed. Use of such third-party sites is subject to the terms of use and privacy statements of those third parties. InstaMed does not control the use of this technology or the resulting information and is not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties.

**4\. How We Use Your Personal Information**

We use your Personal Information to:

  * complete any registration or other information you request online
  * improve this Website
  * improve our products and services, and identify, develop, and offer new or expanded products and services
  * personalize your experience on this Website, and customize the content and/or format of the pages you visit
  * notify you about updates, products, services, and/or special offers from InstaMed, its affiliates, and selected third parties
  * ask you to participate in brief surveys
  * generate aggregate statistical studies and conduct research related to our products and services and the use of this Website

Based upon your specific relationship(s) with InstaMed, we may use your Personal Information in ways described in more detail in one or more Other Agreements.

**5\. Disclosure of Your Personal Information**

We disclose your Personal Information to certain third parties with whom we have a direct or indirect business or contract relationship, to provide the products and services you have requested.

When you request other services, we will provide your personal data to third parties with whom we arrange for those services to be provided. We may also disclose information to third parties that provide administrative or processing services for us, for example, printing, mailing, and/or payment processing.

InstaMed’s use of third parties to provide services to you (e.g., payment services) is subject to the terms of use and privacy policies of those third-party websites and such third parties are responsible or liable for their use of your personal data.

We may also disclose Personal Information collected on this Website, in accordance with applicable law, to assert or defend our rights and property, to prevent harm to others, to collect a debt, or in response to legal processes such as subpoenas. We may also provide (or reserve the right to provide) Personal Information to credit reporting agencies and to cooperate with law enforcement authorities and other governmental authorities consistent with applicable laws.

If you have consented to our doing so, we may also share your personal data with third parties in order that they may offer you information about their goods and services.

Because non-personal information does not personally identify you, we may use or disclose such information for any purpose. In some instances, we may combine non-personal information with Personal Information (such as embedding email addresses in cookies). If we do combine any non-personal information with Personal Information, the combined information will be treated by us as Personal Information in accordance with this Statement.

Based upon your specific relationship(s) with InstaMed, we may disclose your Personal Information in ways described in more detail in one or more Other Agreements.

**6\. Choice to Opt Out**

If you are receiving communications from us, including voicemail or email, but later decide that you would prefer not to receive communications from InstaMed, please contact [support@instamed.com](mailto:support@instamed.com). Remember, however, that InstaMed may still send email or call you in order to provide a product or service that you request.

**7\. Links to Third-Party Sites**

This Website may contain links to other third-party websites. InstaMed does not control the privacy statements or practices of these third-party sites. You should review those statements before providing any information. InstaMed is not responsible for the content or practices of any linked third-party sites, and we provide these links solely for the convenience and information of our visitors. Specifically, if you use a credit card, debit card or bank account information to pay for any products or services, InstaMed is not responsible for any information you provide regarding the credit card, debit card or bank account information on this Website.

**8\. Security**

InstaMed has established safeguards to help prevent unauthorized access to or misuse of your Personal Information, but cannot guarantee that your Personal Information will never be disclosed in a manner inconsistent with this Statement (for example, as a result of unauthorized acts by third parties that violate applicable law or relevant Web statements).

If you register for a Web account, you will be asked to select a password to help protect your information. These passwords help us verify your identity before granting access or making corrections to any of your Personal Information. You should never disclose your password to anyone. InstaMed will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or email. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and any account information.

When you provide credit card, debit card or bank account information, it is transmitted using SSL technology to help prevent unauthorized access to or misuse of that information. You will know that SSL is being used when you see a full yellow key in a blue box in the lower left-hand corner of your browser or a full “lock” in the status bar of your Internet Explorer browser.

**9\. Changes**

InstaMed reserves the right to change this Statement to respond to new laws, regulations, technology, or for other business reasons. Please check this Website from time to time to review any such changes.

**10\. Governing Law and Jurisdiction**

You agree that any claim, action or proceeding arising out of this Statement, or your use of this Website, shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the United States and the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, without regard to principles of conflict of laws. Any claim, action or proceeding related to this Statement will be resolved exclusively in the state or federal courts located in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania and you consent to the jurisdiction of those courts.

**11\. Contact Information**

If you have any questions or concerns about this Website or Privacy Statement, you may contact us by email at [support@instamed.com](mailto:support@instamed.com) or write to us at: InstaMed, Privacy Office, 1880 JFK Boulevard, 12th Floor, Philadelphia, PA 19103.

**12\. Special Notice to California Residents**

Under California Law SB 27, California residents have the right to receive, once a year, information about third parties with whom we have shared Personal Information about you or your family for their marketing purposes during the previous calendar year, and a description of the categories of Personal Information shared. If you are a California resident and wish to make such a request, please send an email to [support@instamed.com](mailto:support@instamed.com) and include the phrase “California Privacy Request” in the subject line, and provide us with your name, address and email address. We will respond to you within thirty (30) days of receiving such a request.

**13\. Do Not Track**

InstaMed supports Do Not Track across all of the pages on its website.  Regardless of whether you activate Do Not Track in your web browser, InstaMed does not track user actions across multiple websites.  InstaMed does use cookies and/or create log entries for access to individual sites that you visit, consistent with this privacy policy.  Do Not Track (DNT) is a privacy preference that you can set in your web browser to indicate that you do not want certain information about your webpage visits collected across websites when you have not interacted with that service on the page. For additional information in regard to Do Not Track, please visit donottrack.us.

**14\. Third Parties**

When you use our website/service, third parties cannot collect personally identifiable information about your online activities.

**15\. Class Action Waiver**

THERE WILL BE NO RIGHT OR AUTHORITY FOR ANY DISPUTE TO BE BROUGHT, HEARD, OR ARBITRATED AS A CLASS ACTION (INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION OPT OUT CLASS ACTIONS OR OPT IN COLLECTIVE CLASS ACTIONS), OR IN A REPRESENTATIVE OR PRIVATE ATTORNEY GENERAL CAPACITY ON BEHALF OF A CLASS OF PERSONS OR THE GENERAL PUBLIC.  ALL DISPUTES SHALL BE RESOLVED ON AN INDIVIDUAL BASIS ONLY.

**See also:**

  * Site Terms of Use

**_This Privacy Statement_** **_is effective as of: December 18, 2013_**
